Hey guys welcome back.
So now we are finally here.
We are going to execute the project.
All your planning all the document creation has done of course we'll continue to update them.
But now it's time to push everything start project and don't that if you have already gone through all
these processes so manage indirect work or develop them.
All of these things have been discussed in all the knowledge areas.
We just need to put everything together and do whatever is needed to push a project.
So basically executing process group and consists of those processes which are require to complete the
work which is defined in the project management plan.
For example business analysis or coding.
So if we have decided that we need to go to a website now we need to start the coding if we need to
gather the requirement we need to start together.
In general this is the phase from where the actual work start.
So the sponsors and the senior management takes the back seat.
Project manager and the development team takes the front seat.
So now a business analyst for The Star.
The common collections and their management prioritization and how they will be delivered.
That is release management programmers when they start to analyze the changes they will start to prepare
the technical analysis documents of course they will have their own floor the sequence of their activities.
But the real work will happen if you are in some other industry in showed in construction the execution
style.
This is at this stage at this stage you spend most of your money.
So this is where you need all those foreigns budgets estimations Gene's request are usually generated
in this.
All those change management plans and practices which you established earlier.
Now they will be required.
You have to have a good plan my friend.
As a project manager it is your responsibility to make sure that everything is following the plan falling
plan is the key word here.
You have to be very careful with that.
So whether its business analysis coding testing or construction whatever you are going to do that should
follow the plan because if Zendik was approved then you will have more work.
So you need to have plan for everything.
And launching a project acquired some of these basic steps.
I mean they have drawn these steps based on my experience.
It could be slightly different for you but a higher level more or less things are seen.
So it is at this stage to launch the project.
Project manager will acquire the team and that is human resource and other physical resources.
And then project managers work with their team and communicate project standards and guidelines.
So basically these processes has been planned earlier.
Project manager is explaining the deliverables which are expected out of them communicating to them
in terms of how communication will happen costs the source and everything and formally our project managers
will hold a kickoff meeting this kickoff meeting will basically include information about the deliverables
and timelines rules and responsibilities and guidelines kickoff meeting is very important and it always
helps to bring everyone on same page because even before the project is started formally most of the
team members when they start to get information but that information is in bits and pieces.
They dont have the complete picture.
They may not even know all the team members so this kick off meeting said the purpose of bringing everyone
together.
They all know the rules and responsibilities the standards deliverables how they should raise their
concern if any and executing process group will include all these sub processes which have been taken
from all those knowledge.
We have covered so far.
So we have already gone through that act and managed project.
This is where our project manager is using the leadership qualities to direct and manage project for
the actual Varg business analysis coding testing those kind of things then managing the project knowledge
how we are going to store the knowledge and information and how we are going to communicate that quality
will be managed here.
If any of the sources that acquired that acquisition will happen here delaminating will happen here.
Managing time will happen here.
Then of course the communication management and implemented all those plans are the sponsors along with
conducting any procurements if needed and a stickler management will happen in all the processes and
subprocesses and the phases of the project.
So thats going to be here but largely There is nothing new.
Its just that you are putting these things in a particular sequence.
If we had that correspondence project number project manager will acquire those resources which are
needed.
It would be our software if any human resource is going to be there.
So the business analyst programmers testers all those individuals who are going to work on the project
project you will acquire them.
They will be assigned their roles and responsibilities.
Project managers will share the WB a score which they will use for billing and adding them in their
time sheet.
Project manager will share the guidelines about knowledge management practices knowledge transfer practices
standard practices for communication like you know who are the key stakeholders.
For example business analyst will need that information for the common gathering.
So project manager will share that information and project manager will direct and manage project work
like coding testing analysis construction whatever work is needed there.
If any procurement is needed project manager is going to perform that.
So it's a cycle.
Basically you first initiate the process which is creating your project charter and I didn't define
stakeholder.
Then you move a step ahead.
You create all those plans based on the information you have.
So you create plans for this management do you create a plan for communication you create a plan for
quieting the sources managing your knowledge.
Now you have moved a step ahead.
This is very good putting everything to work and whatever work is needed here is being done and project
manager is serving as a leader in case of an methodologies that could be scrum master who call themselves
Sortiment coaches.
But the skills and the rule is of leadership.
So don't get confused if you come across a term which is like solving course in terms of dieter's.
We have already covered these processes so that sit in the next video we will talk about the next process.
Thank you.